<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Internet on Cse Tutorials</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/topics/internet/</link><description>Recent content in Internet on Cse Tutorials</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2020 00:19:00 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://csetutorials.com/topics/internet/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Top Chrome Extensions for Advanced users and Developers</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/top-chrome-extensions-for-advanced-users-and-developers/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2020 09:10:36 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://csetutorials.com/top-chrome-extensions-for-advanced-users-and-developers/</guid><description>Below is the list of extensions that every developer should install in their Chrome browser. These plugins make the life of developers easy.
Below is the list of extensions that every developer should install in their Chrome browser. These plugins make the life of developers easy.
Adblock Plus : Improves readability of site by blocking all ADDS
Ghostery : Improves browsing experience and speed by blocking all trackers like Analytics, Advertising, Beacons, Privacy and Widgets.</description></item><item><title>How to create a seedbox using AWS</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/create-seedbox-aws/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Mar 2020 07:14:31 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://csetutorials.com/create-seedbox-aws/</guid><description>In this article I&amp;rsquo;m going to tell you how to create a seedbox using AWS (Amazon Web Service). Using seedbox we can download torrent files like Ubuntu disk image etc.
To create a seedbox first I will create a aws lambda instance (virtual machine) and then activate seedbox using cloud-torrent. So here are the steps.
1. Login to you aws account. If you don&amp;rsquo;t have an aws account then create it and then login.</description></item><item><title>The Finest Android Apps</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/android-apps/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2017 06:26:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://csetutorials.com/android-apps/</guid><description>Busybox (Root Required) : This application is an BusyBox installer for Android.
Flud : Flud is a simple and beautiful BitTorrent client. It is better that utorrent and any other torrent clients available on play store.
Gallery Doctor : It identifies similar, duplicate and bad quality photos and gives you an option to remove them. It is very helpful to remove unwanted whatsapp photos.
Greenify : It forcefully kills apps like facebook and whatsapp that runs in the background, consuming battery and internet bandwidth, push annoying notification.</description></item></channel></rss>