<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cloud on Cse Tutorials</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/topics/cloud/</link><description>Recent content in Cloud on Cse Tutorials</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2024 03:59:37 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://csetutorials.com/topics/cloud/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Content Delivery Networks (CDNs) Explained: A Beginner &amp; Intermediate Guide</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/content-delivery-networks-cdn-guide.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2024 03:59:37 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://csetutorials.com/content-delivery-networks-cdn-guide.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="what-is-a-cdn">What is a CDN?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>A CDN, or Content Delivery Network, is a network of servers spread across different geographical locations that work together to deliver web content to users efficiently. When a user seeks a webpage or any other form of content, the CDN automatically identifies the nearest server to the user and delivers the content from there. This helps to reduce latency and improve the overall performance of the website.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Conquer VPC Networking: Subnets &amp; CIDR Allocation Mastery</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/vpc-networking-subnet-cidr-beginner-guide.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 11:11:33 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://csetutorials.com/vpc-networking-subnet-cidr-beginner-guide.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="cidr-notation-and-ip-address-allocation">CIDR Notation and IP Address Allocation&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>CIDR notation is a fundamental concept in networking that allows for efficient allocation of IP addresses. It provides a way to represent IP addresses and their associated subnet masks in a compact and easy-to-understand format. By using CIDR notation, network administrators can allocate IP addresses in a flexible and scalable manner.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In CIDR notation, an IP address is followed by a forward slash (/) and a number, which represents the number of network bits in the address. The network bits are used to identify the network portion of the IP address, while the remaining bits are used for host addresses. This allows for efficient allocation of IP addresses, as the network bits can be adjusted to accommodate different network sizes.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Public Cloud Demystified: Everything You Need to Know</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/public-cloud-beginner-guide.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 17:38:04 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://csetutorials.com/public-cloud-beginner-guide.html</guid><description>&lt;p>A public cloud refers to a type of cloud computing service that is available to the general public over the internet. It is owned and operated by a third-party cloud service provider, who is responsible for managing and maintaining the infrastructure and resources.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One of the key characteristics of a public cloud is its multi-tenancy nature. This means that multiple users or organizations can share the same pool of computing resources, such as servers, storage, and networks. These resources are dynamically allocated and can be scaled up or down based on the needs of the users.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hybrid Cloud: The Best of Both Cloud Worlds</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/hybrid-cloud-beginner-guide.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 09:49:37 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://csetutorials.com/hybrid-cloud-beginner-guide.html</guid><description>&lt;p>A hybrid cloud is a computing environment that combines the use of both private and public cloud services. It allows organizations to leverage the benefits of both types of clouds, creating a flexible and scalable infrastructure that meets their specific needs.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-does-a-hybrid-cloud-work">How Does a Hybrid Cloud Work?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In a hybrid cloud environment, organizations typically have a private cloud infrastructure that is located on-premises or in a dedicated data center. This private cloud is connected to one or more public cloud providers through a secure network connection.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Private Cloud 101: Your Guide to a Secure &amp; Tailored IT Environment</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/private-cloud-explained-for-beginners.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2024 18:23:42 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://csetutorials.com/private-cloud-explained-for-beginners.html</guid><description>&lt;p>In today&amp;rsquo;s digital age, cloud computing has revolutionized the way businesses operate and manage their IT infrastructure. It offers a flexible and scalable solution that allows organizations to access and utilize computing resources over the internet. One of the key variations of cloud computing is the private cloud, which provides a secure and tailored IT environment for businesses.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>A private cloud is a cloud setup specifically for one organization&amp;rsquo;s use. Unlike public clouds that are shared by multiple users, a private cloud is designed to meet the specific needs of an individual business. It can be hosted on-premises or by a third-party service provider, and it offers a higher level of control and security compared to public clouds.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Community Cloud: The Shared Secret to Secure Collaboration</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/community-cloud-computing.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2024 18:14:04 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://csetutorials.com/community-cloud-computing.html</guid><description>&lt;p>A community cloud is a type of cloud computing infrastructure that is shared by specific organizations with common interests. It provides a collaborative platform for these organizations to share resources, applications, and data securely. Unlike public clouds that are available to anyone, and private clouds that are dedicated to a single organization, community clouds are designed to meet the unique needs of a specific community.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In a community cloud, multiple organizations with similar requirements come together to pool their resources and create a shared infrastructure. This infrastructure is then managed by a third-party cloud service provider, who ensures the security, availability, and maintenance of the community cloud. Each organization within the community has its own private space within the cloud, where they can store and access their data and applications.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Unlock the Cloud: What is SaaS &amp; Why You Need It</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/software-as-a-service-beginner-guide.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2024 11:43:49 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://csetutorials.com/software-as-a-service-beginner-guide.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Imagine a time when using a software program meant physically going to a store, purchasing a box with CDs or DVDs containing the software, and then installing it on your computer. Not too long ago, this was standard practice. Thankfully, today we have a more convenient way to access software: Software as a Service (SaaS). Think of it as software that lives on the internet, accessible from any device with a web browser, just like your favourite social media platform or online bank. This is the core idea behind SaaS - software delivered as an online service, eliminating the need for physical installations or downloads.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Build Like a Pro: Demystifying PaaS for App Development Newbies</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/platform-as-a-service-beginner-guide.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2024 06:17:33 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://csetutorials.com/platform-as-a-service-beginner-guide.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Imagine you&amp;rsquo;re building a house. You can approach it in three ways:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Buying the Land and Building Materials (IaaS) :&lt;/strong> This is like starting from scratch. You&amp;rsquo;d need to buy the land (physical servers), bricks (storage), and lumber (networking) to build your house (application). It gives you the most control, but it&amp;rsquo;s also the most time-consuming and expensive option.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Hiring a Contractor with Prefabricated Walls (PaaS) :&lt;/strong> This is like using a PaaS platform. The contractor (PaaS provider) has a pre-built foundation, walls, and roof (development tools, databases, runtime environment). You can customize the interior and choose the finishing touches (develop your application logic). While PaaS offers speed and cost savings, you sacrifice some control over the underlying infrastructure.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Say Goodbye to Hardware Hassle: The Simple Guide to IaaS</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/infrastructure-as-a-service.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 10:22:05 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://csetutorials.com/infrastructure-as-a-service.html</guid><description>&lt;p>IaaS, or Infrastructure as a Service, is a transformative concept in cloud computing that offers a way to rent essential IT infrastructure, rather than owning and maintaining it yourself. It&amp;rsquo;s like subscribing to a utility instead of building your own power plant. This shift from physical hardware to virtual resources unlocks a treasure trove of benefits for businesses of all sizes:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Reduced upfront costs:&lt;/strong> IaaS eliminates the need for hefty upfront investments in physical hardware. Servers, storage units, and networking equipment can be incredibly expensive, and they often become obsolete before their lifespan is over. IaaS frees you from this financial burden, allowing you to scale your IT infrastructure up or down based on your needs, without the sunk costs of underutilized equipment.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What is Amazon Web Services</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/what-is-amazon-web-services.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2018 10:39:52 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://csetutorials.com/what-is-amazon-web-services.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Let&amp;rsquo;s imagine how life would have been without Spotify. For those who are hearing about Spotify for the first time, Spotify is an online music service offering and it offers instant access to over 16 million licence to songs. Spotify now uses AWS cloud to store the data and share it with their customers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Prior to AWS they had some issues. Back then users were often getting errors because Spotify could not keep up with the increased demand for storage every new day and that led to users getting upset and users canceling the subscription.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>