<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Pages on Cse Tutorials</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/pages/</link><description>Recent content in Pages on Cse Tutorials</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://csetutorials.com/pages/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>About us</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/about-us/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csetutorials.com/about-us/</guid><description>&lt;p>My name is Ashish Doneriya. I am a Software Engineer. I graduated from Maulana Azad National Institute of Technology. I live in Indore, India. In csetutorials.com I post article about the tools and technologies that I have used before and wanted to share my information about that. I started blogging for the purpose of learning and sharing information.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Contact us</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/contact-us/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csetutorials.com/contact-us/</guid><description>&lt;iframe src="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSei0rz9JBzkN8HKusoWbbypJUul54zDt1vxJTRto3mqAx6jvA/viewform?embedded=true" width="640" height="800" frameborder="0" marginheight="0" marginwidth="0">Loading…&lt;/iframe></description></item><item><title>Privacy Policy</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/privacy-policy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csetutorials.com/privacy-policy/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="who-we-are">Who we are&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Our website address is: &lt;a href="https://csetutorials.com">https://csetutorials.com&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="comments">Comments&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>When visitors leave comments on the site we collect the data shown in the comments form, and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>An anonymized string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service to see if you are using it. The Gravatar service privacy policy is available here: &lt;a href="https://automattic.com/privacy/">https://automattic.com/privacy/&lt;/a>. After approval of your comment, your profile picture is visible to the public in the context of your comment.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Terms of Service</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/terms-of-service/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://csetutorials.com/terms-of-service/</guid><description>&lt;p>The following terms and conditions govern all use of the csetutorials.com website and all content, services and products available at or through the website (taken together, the Website). The Website is owned and operated by CseTutorials (&amp;ldquo;CseTutorials&amp;rdquo;). The Website is offered subject to your acceptance without modification of all of the terms and conditions contained herein and all other operating rules, policies (including, without limitation, CseTutorials&amp;rsquo;s Privacy Policy) and procedures that may be published from time to time on this Site by CseTutorials (collectively, the &amp;ldquo;Agreement&amp;rdquo;).&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>