<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Cse Tutorials</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Cse Tutorials</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 04:26:25 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://csetutorials.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Everything About Docker Storage Drivers</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/docker-storage-drivers-explained/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 04:26:25 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://csetutorials.com/docker-storage-drivers-explained/</guid><description>When you run a container in Docker, it needs to read and write files just like any other application. But since containers are isolated environments, they can&amp;rsquo;t just write files anywhere on your system. This is where Docker storage drivers come in. They manage how files are stored, shared, and accessed within Docker containers. Different storage drivers have different ways of handling this, affecting speed, efficiency, and compatibility.
What is a Docker Storage Driver?</description></item><item><title>How WhatsApp Manages Real-Time Messaging at Scale: A Detailed Guide</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/whatsapp-real-time-messaging-scalability/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 20:10:04 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://csetutorials.com/whatsapp-real-time-messaging-scalability/</guid><description>WhatsApp, with billions of active users, manages an enormous volume of real-time messages daily while maintaining seamless performance, scalability, and end-to-end encryption. This article provides a comprehensive look into WhatsApp’s message delivery system, focusing on its architecture, handling of one-to-one and group chats, offline message storage, notification mechanisms, optimized database operations, and efficient user-to-server mapping.
WhatsApp Messaging Architecture: An Overview WhatsApp’s infrastructure relies on multiple components to deliver real-time communication:</description></item><item><title>Understanding Push Notifications in WhatsApp: Architecture, Flow, and Behavior</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/push-notifications-whatsapp-architecture-flow/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 18:35:38 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://csetutorials.com/push-notifications-whatsapp-architecture-flow/</guid><description>Understanding Push Notifications: Architecture and Flow Push notifications are a core feature in modern apps, enabling real-time communication with users. Whether it’s a messaging app like WhatsApp or a social media platform, the process involves multiple components working together seamlessly. Let’s break it down step by step.
Push Notification Architecture The architecture of push notifications is built around three key players:
Mobile App: The app installed on the user’s device that wants to notify the user about certain events.</description></item><item><title>Setting Up Master-Master Replication in MariaDB on Ubuntu: A Comprehensive Guide</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/master-master-replication-mariadb-ubuntu-setup/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 21:06:26 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://csetutorials.com/master-master-replication-mariadb-ubuntu-setup/</guid><description>Master-Master replication in MariaDB enables active-active replication, allowing both servers to handle reads and writes, and synchronize changes with each other. This setup improves availability and redundancy but requires careful configuration to avoid conflicts.
This guide will walk you through the full setup, covering error logging configuration, network access, and conflict prevention settings.
Prerequisites Two Ubuntu Servers with static IPs: Server A IP: 91.107.235.82 Server B IP: 188.34.176.130 Root or sudo access on both servers.</description></item><item><title>Understanding NiFi and Airflow in Simple Terms: How They Help with Data Engineering and Data Flow</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/nifi-vs-airflow-real-time-vs-batch/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 06:40:58 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://csetutorials.com/nifi-vs-airflow-real-time-vs-batch/</guid><description>In the world of data, things can get pretty complex. Companies have tons of data flowing in from different sources—like websites, sensors, apps, or databases—and they need ways to handle and process all of this information. Two tools that help manage this data are Apache NiFi and Apache Airflow. They do different jobs, but both are very important when it comes to making sure data is handled properly. Let’s break it down in simple terms.</description></item><item><title>My AWS Revision Notes</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/my-aws-revision-notes/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2024 10:42:27 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://csetutorials.com/my-aws-revision-notes/</guid><description>Outpost Use Cases:
• Used for compliance or very low latency, such as in regions like Jammu &amp;amp; Kashmir.
AWS Availability Zones (AZ) &amp;amp; Local Zones:
• AZ (Availability Zone): Provides high availability within a region.
• Local Zone: Limited services like database and EC2, close to users (e.g., Bengaluru), used to reduce latency. Example use case: Netflix. Local Zones offer single-digit millisecond latency but cost slightly more.
• More information: AWS Global Infrastructure.</description></item><item><title>Understanding List, Get and Put Permissions in Amazon S3</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/s3-list-get-put-permissions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 16:25:52 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://csetutorials.com/s3-list-get-put-permissions/</guid><description>Amazon S3 is a widely used storage service where permissions are controlled through AWS Identity and Access Management (IAM) policies. These policies specify what actions users or services can perform on S3 buckets and their contents.
In S3, permissions are granted using ARNs (Amazon Resource Names) that identify specific resources. There are two key types of ARNs when dealing with S3 permissions:
arn:aws:s3:::mybucket : This refers to the bucket. arn:aws:s3:::mybucket/* : This refers to all the objects (files) within the bucket.</description></item><item><title>AWS Auto Scaling Group: EC2 and ELB Health Checks Explained</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/aws-asg-ec2-elb-health-checks/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2024 13:40:02 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://csetutorials.com/aws-asg-ec2-elb-health-checks/</guid><description>When managing your application’s infrastructure on AWS, Elastic Load Balancers (ELBs) and Auto Scaling Groups (ASGs) work together to ensure high availability and scalability. Both components perform health checks to determine the status of your EC2 instances, but they operate differently, and understanding how they interact is essential for smooth operation.
In this article, we will explore how ELB health checks and ASG health checks work, their differences, and why it’s important to configure them correctly.</description></item><item><title>AWS Storage Gateway: Key Differences Between File Gateway and Volume Gateway</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/aws-storage-gateway-file-gateway-vs-volume-gateway/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2024 18:34:10 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://csetutorials.com/aws-storage-gateway-file-gateway-vs-volume-gateway/</guid><description>AWS Storage Gateway is a hybrid cloud storage service that enables organizations to connect their on-premises applications with cloud storage in AWS. Among its offerings, File Gateway and Volume Gateway are two key components designed to meet different storage needs. This article explores the key differences between File Gateway and Volume Gateway, helping you understand when to use each service based on your specific requirements.
Benefits of File Gateway and Volume Gateway File Gateway Provides an easy way to store and manage files in the cloud, offering seamless integration with existing applications.</description></item><item><title>Effective Maintenance Strategies for EC2 Instances in Auto Scaling Groups</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/ec2-maintenance-strategies-auto-scaling-groups/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 19:19:50 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://csetutorials.com/ec2-maintenance-strategies-auto-scaling-groups/</guid><description>Maintaining Amazon EC2 instances that are part of an Auto Scaling group can present unique challenges, especially when it comes to ensuring minimal downtime and maintaining the overall health of your application. This article explores various strategies for performing maintenance on EC2 instances within an Auto Scaling group while minimizing the risk of instance replacement and service disruption.
Challenge During Maintenance When performing maintenance tasks, such as applying patches or updates, instances may temporarily fail health checks, leading Auto Scaling to replace them.</description></item><item><title>AWS S3 Transfer Acceleration and Multipart Upload Costs and Failures</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/aws-s3-transfer-acceleration-multipart-upload-costs-failures/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 06:13:44 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://csetutorials.com/aws-s3-transfer-acceleration-multipart-upload-costs-failures/</guid><description>When using Amazon S3 (Simple Storage Service), understanding how charges apply to data transfers can help you optimize costs and performance, especially when using advanced features like S3 Transfer Acceleration (S3TA) and multipart upload. This article breaks down the costs involved in using these features, and what happens if transfers fail.
Standard AWS S3 Data Transfer Costs By default, AWS charges for data transferred in and out of S3 as follows:</description></item><item><title>Understanding AMI vs. Snapshot in AWS: Key Differences, Creation Process, and Cross-Region Usage</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/aws-ami-vs-snapshot-differences-cross-region/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 05:37:05 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://csetutorials.com/aws-ami-vs-snapshot-differences-cross-region/</guid><description>In AWS, when working with EC2 instances, two important concepts you need to know about are AMI (Amazon Machine Image) and Snapshot. These two features allow you to manage your instances and data efficiently, but they serve different purposes. This article will explain the key differences, how they are created, and how to work with AMIs across AWS regions.
What is an AMI (Amazon Machine Image)? An Amazon Machine Image (AMI) is essentially a blueprint used to launch an EC2 instance.</description></item><item><title>Understanding AWS RDS Replication: Synchronous Multi-AZ vs. Asynchronous Read Replicas</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/aws-rds-multi-az-vs-read-replicas-replication/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 21:06:20 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://csetutorials.com/aws-rds-multi-az-vs-read-replicas-replication/</guid><description>Amazon Web Services (AWS) Relational Database Service (RDS) offers powerful features for database replication and high availability. Two key features are Multi-AZ deployments and Read Replicas. Understanding how these features work, their differences, and how they impact data consistency and scalability is crucial for architects and developers.
This article delves into the replication mechanisms of AWS RDS Multi-AZ deployments and Read Replicas, explores the challenges of achieving strong data consistency while scaling read operations, and discusses strategies to balance these requirements.</description></item><item><title>Understanding Multithreading and Asyncio in Python: A Deep Dive into I/O-bound Task Management</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/multithreading-vs-asyncio-python-io-bound-tasks/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 15:38:21 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://csetutorials.com/multithreading-vs-asyncio-python-io-bound-tasks/</guid><description>When building applications in Python, particularly those that handle numerous I/O-bound tasks (e.g., file reading/writing, network requests), choosing the right concurrency model—multithreading or asyncio—is crucial for performance. Both approaches aim to optimize how tasks are executed concurrently, but they differ in how they handle context switching, resource management, and complexity. In this article, we’ll explore the nuances, concerns, and trade-offs of multithreading and asyncio in Python, especially when dealing with I/O-bound tasks.</description></item><item><title>A Comprehensive Guide to Amazon S3 Cross-Region Replication: Setup, Versioning and Best Practices</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/s3-cross-region-replication-setup/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 15:10:52 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://csetutorials.com/s3-cross-region-replication-setup/</guid><description>Amazon S3 (Simple Storage Service) is a scalable, reliable storage solution that serves a wide range of applications. One of its key features is Cross-Region Replication (CRR), which allows you to automatically copy objects from a source S3 bucket in one AWS region to a destination bucket in another region. This is particularly useful for ensuring data redundancy, improving performance for users in different regions, and meeting compliance and disaster recovery requirements.</description></item><item><title>Understanding EC2 Network Types in Amazon ECS: A Simple Guide</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/ec2-network-types-amazon-ecs-guide/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 15:02:03 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://csetutorials.com/ec2-network-types-amazon-ecs-guide/</guid><description>When using Amazon ECS (Elastic Container Service) with the EC2 launch type, choosing the correct network mode is crucial for how your containers communicate with each other and the outside world. This guide will explain the different network types available in ECS in simple terms and give real-world examples to help you understand which one to use for your specific needs.
EC2 Network Types in ECS There are four main network modes available in ECS when using the EC2 launch type: Bridge Mode, Host Mode, Awsvpc Mode, and None Mode.</description></item><item><title>Mastering S3 Access Control: Bucket Policies, IAM Policies, and S3 Access Points Explained</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/s3-access-control-bucket-policies-iam-access-points/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2024 03:36:57 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://csetutorials.com/s3-access-control-bucket-policies-iam-access-points/</guid><description>When working with Amazon S3, securing your data is a top priority. One powerful way to manage who can access your S3 bucket and under what conditions is by using bucket policies. These policies consist of different elements, two of which are the Principal element and the Condition element.
In this article, I will explain what the Principal and Condition elements are, how they work, and how you can use them to control access to your S3 bucket.</description></item><item><title>AWS Client VPN: Secure Remote Access Solution for Individual Users</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/aws-client-vpn-secure-remote-access-individual-users/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2024 17:55:32 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://csetutorials.com/aws-client-vpn-secure-remote-access-individual-users/</guid><description>In today&amp;rsquo;s world, where remote work and third-party collaborations are common, businesses need secure ways for employees, contractors, or vendors to access their internal systems and cloud resources. This is where AWS Client VPN comes into play. It offers a simple, secure, and cost-effective way for individuals to remotely access Amazon Web Services (AWS) resources or on-premises systems. In this article, we will explore what AWS Client VPN is, how it works, how it differs from AWS Site-to-Site VPN and AWS Direct Connect, and some common use cases.</description></item><item><title>Understanding AWS Organizations: Consolidated Billing vs All Features</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/aws-organizations-consolidated-billing-all-features/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2024 15:40:54 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://csetutorials.com/aws-organizations-consolidated-billing-all-features/</guid><description>As businesses grow, so does their need to manage multiple AWS accounts efficiently. AWS Organizations helps by allowing you to manage and organize multiple accounts under a single umbrella. When setting up an AWS Organization, you&amp;rsquo;re given two choices: Consolidated billing or All features. Each option serves a different purpose, and understanding these options can help you manage your AWS resources more effectively.
Let&amp;rsquo;s break down what these options mean, how they work, and when to use them.</description></item><item><title>Understanding the Amazon S3 Glacier Restore Process: How It Works, Request Types, and Key Considerations</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/s3-glacier-restore-process-retrieval-options/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2024 14:00:11 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://csetutorials.com/s3-glacier-restore-process-retrieval-options/</guid><description>Amazon S3 Glacier and Glacier Deep Archive are cost-effective storage classes designed for long-term archival of data that is infrequently accessed. These storage classes provide durability and low-cost storage, making them ideal for regulatory, compliance, or backup purposes. However, when you need to retrieve data from S3 Glacier or Glacier Deep Archive, you must initiate a restore process to temporarily make the data accessible.
In this article, I’ll explain how the restore process works, the different restore request types, and discuss the free tier options that can impact the cost of Glacier restores.</description></item><item><title>Understanding AWS Storage Gateway Types: Cached Volumes, Stored Volumes and Tape Gateway</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/aws-storage-gateway-cached-stored-volumes-tape/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2024 12:48:31 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://csetutorials.com/aws-storage-gateway-cached-stored-volumes-tape/</guid><description>AWS Storage Gateway offers several solutions to seamlessly extend on-premises storage infrastructure to the cloud. These solutions allow businesses to benefit from the scalability, durability, and cost efficiency of AWS while retaining the necessary on-premises storage for critical use cases. Among the Storage Gateway options are Gateway Cached Volumes, Gateway Stored Volumes, and Tape Gateway. Each provides different benefits depending on how much data is stored on-premises versus in the cloud, and how data is accessed and backed up.</description></item><item><title>S3 Pre-Signed URLs vs. CloudFront Signed URLs and Cookies: A Complete Comparison</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/s3-cloudfront-signed-urls-signed-cookies-comparison/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2024 10:44:18 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://csetutorials.com/s3-cloudfront-signed-urls-signed-cookies-comparison/</guid><description>AWS offers several ways to secure access to content stored in Amazon S3, including S3 Pre-Signed URLs, CloudFront Signed URLs, and CloudFront Signed Cookies. Each solution has distinct use cases, especially when it comes to performance, security, and whether users need access to single or multiple files. Additionally, CloudFront Signed URLs do not support uploads, which is a key factor to consider when deciding between these options.
In this guide, I&amp;rsquo;ll cover the differences between these three methods, explain when to use each one, and provide real-world examples of the best use cases for each solution.</description></item><item><title>CloudWatch vs. CloudTrail: Comprehensive Guide to AWS Monitoring, Logging, and Auditing</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/cloudwatch-vs-cloudtrail-usecases-monitoring-auditing/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2024 08:19:35 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://csetutorials.com/cloudwatch-vs-cloudtrail-usecases-monitoring-auditing/</guid><description>When working with AWS infrastructure, two services play essential roles in monitoring and management: Amazon CloudWatch and AWS CloudTrail.
Although both are essential, they fulfill distinct roles. This guide will explore the differences between CloudWatch and CloudTrail, when to use each, and how they apply to key AWS services like S3, DynamoDB, API Gateway, and EC2. We will also delve into access logs and execution logs, two critical concepts for tracking the performance and functionality of your services.</description></item><item><title>AWS Gateway Endpoint vs Interface Endpoint: Limitations &amp; Use Cases</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/aws-gateway-vs-interface-endpoint-differences-use-cases/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2024 05:17:54 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://csetutorials.com/aws-gateway-vs-interface-endpoint-differences-use-cases/</guid><description>When designing applications on AWS, ensuring secure and efficient communication between your Virtual Private Cloud (VPC) and AWS services is crucial. AWS provides VPC Endpoints to enable private connections between your VPC and supported AWS services, keeping traffic within AWS&amp;rsquo;s internal network and avoiding the public internet. This not only enhances security but also optimizes performance.
AWS offers two types of VPC Endpoints: Gateway Endpoints and Interface Endpoints. Both serve different purposes and are designed for specific AWS services.</description></item><item><title>Optimizing AWS Application Load Balancer for High Availability and Efficient Traffic Handling</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/aws-alb-high-availability-traffic-optimization/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2024 17:51:38 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://csetutorials.com/aws-alb-high-availability-traffic-optimization/</guid><description>Amazon Web Services (AWS) offers various load balancing options, with the Application Load Balancer (ALB) being widely used for distributing HTTP/HTTPS traffic. This article covers the core concepts of ALB, including how it integrates with Availability Zones (AZs) and subnets, its role in instance scaling, and the use of warmup conditions—all of which are essential for handling traffic efficiently and securely.
Key Concepts of Load Balancers in AWS Load balancers distribute incoming requests across multiple Amazon EC2 instances, ensuring no single server becomes overwhelmed.</description></item><item><title>Understanding AWS X-Ray &amp; Its Use Cases</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/aws-xray-tracing-debugging-guide/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 16:17:14 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://csetutorials.com/aws-xray-tracing-debugging-guide/</guid><description>What AWS X-Ray Does Tracing: X-Ray traces the entire path of a request as it moves through different components of an application, especially in microservice architectures. Each step or service that the request touches is recorded, and X-Ray provides a visual map of how the request moves across various AWS services.
Debugging: With X-Ray, you can debug performance bottlenecks, errors, and latency issues by identifying where things go wrong in your application (e.</description></item><item><title>Content Delivery Networks (CDNs) Explained: A Beginner &amp; Intermediate Guide</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/content-delivery-networks-cdn-guide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2024 03:59:37 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://csetutorials.com/content-delivery-networks-cdn-guide/</guid><description>What is a CDN? A CDN, or Content Delivery Network, is a network of servers spread across different geographical locations that work together to deliver web content to users efficiently. When a user seeks a webpage or any other form of content, the CDN automatically identifies the nearest server to the user and delivers the content from there. This helps to reduce latency and improve the overall performance of the website.</description></item><item><title>Enhance Cloud Performance with Multicast on AWS</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/aws-multicast-guide-transit-gateway/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2024 02:52:45 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://csetutorials.com/aws-multicast-guide-transit-gateway/</guid><description>In this article, I will explore the concept of multicast and how it can be implemented using AWS Transit Gateways. Multicast is a powerful networking technology that allows efficient distribution of data to multiple recipients. By leveraging AWS Transit Gateways, you can take advantage of this technology in your cloud infrastructure.
Multicast is a communication method that enables a single data stream to be sent to multiple recipients simultaneously. This is in contrast to unicast, where data is sent from a single source to a single destination.</description></item><item><title>AWS Direct Connect Gateway: The Key to Scalable &amp; Reliable Hybrid Cloud</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/aws-direct-connect-gateway-beginner-guide/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2024 09:33:17 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://csetutorials.com/aws-direct-connect-gateway-beginner-guide/</guid><description>The AWS Direct Connect Gateway is a powerful tool that enables businesses to establish secure and reliable network connections between their on-premises data centers and their Amazon Virtual Private Clouds (VPCs) across different AWS regions. By acting as a central hub for connecting multiple VPCs, the Direct Connect Gateway simplifies network management and enhances the overall performance and scalability of your AWS infrastructure.
Key Advantages Dedicated Connections One of the key benefits of using the AWS Direct Connect Gateway is the ability to establish private network connections, also known as dedicated connections, which offer higher bandwidth and lower latency compared to public internet connections.</description></item><item><title>AWS Transit Gateway: A Deep Dive into Architecture</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/aws-transit-gateway-architecture-components/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2024 05:40:37 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://csetutorials.com/aws-transit-gateway-architecture-components/</guid><description>AWS Transit Gateway provides a centralized solution for managing network connectivity across multiple VPCs and on-premises networks. With traditional networking models, connecting multiple VPCs and on-premises networks can be a complex and time-consuming process. However, with the introduction of AWS Transit Gateway, managing network infrastructure has become much simpler and more efficient. If you want to know more about transit gateway then you can read our previous article. Now lets understand various components of transit gateway first.</description></item><item><title>Mastering AWS Transit Gateway: Solutions, Benefits and Optimization</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/aws-transit-gateway-benefits-security-cost-optimization/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2024 10:30:44 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://csetutorials.com/aws-transit-gateway-benefits-security-cost-optimization/</guid><description>Managing network configurations in AWS can be a daunting task, especially when dealing with intricate setups involving multiple VPCs and on-premises connections. While AWS offers great flexibility and scalability, it also presents unique challenges that can make network management a hair-pulling experience.
1. VPC Maze: Navigating the Complexity
With multiple VPCs, each with its own subnets, route tables, and security groups, managing network configurations can quickly become a labyrinthine endeavor. It&amp;rsquo;s easy to get lost in the maze of VPCs, especially when trying to ensure proper connectivity between them and with on-premises resources.</description></item><item><title>AWS VPC PrivateLink: Securely Access AWS Services over a Private Network Connection</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/aws-vpc-privatelink/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2024 06:49:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://csetutorials.com/aws-vpc-privatelink/</guid><description>AWS VPC PrivateLink is a revolutionary service that has transformed the way organizations access and interact with AWS services. In the past, organizations had to rely on public internet connections to access these services, which posed significant security risks. However, with VPC PrivateLink, organizations can now establish a private network connection to AWS services, ensuring the confidentiality and integrity of their data.
Key Advantages Security One of the key advantages of VPC PrivateLink is its ability to provide a secure and scalable way to connect your VPC to AWS services.</description></item><item><title>Demystifying VPC Endpoints: Gateway &amp; Interface for Enhanced AWS Security</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/aws-vpc-endpoints-gateway-interface/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2024 05:09:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://csetutorials.com/aws-vpc-endpoints-gateway-interface/</guid><description>Imagine a scenario where you have an Amazon VPC and you want to access AWS services such as Amazon S3 or DynamoDB from within your VPC. Traditionally, you would have to route the traffic through the internet gateway and back to the AWS service. This not only adds unnecessary network latency but also exposes your resources to potential security risks.
This is where the AWS VPC Endpoint comes into play. It is a horizontally scaled, redundant, and highly available service that enables you to privately connect your VPC to supported AWS services without requiring an internet gateway or NAT device.</description></item><item><title>Managing Infrastructure on AWS: DNS, Route 53, DHCP Server, and DHCP Options Set</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/dns-dhcp-aws-route-53-options-sets/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2024 17:19:07 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://csetutorials.com/dns-dhcp-aws-route-53-options-sets/</guid><description>One of the key concepts that you need to understand when working with AWS is DNS, which stands for Domain Name System. DNS is responsible for translating human-readable domain names, such as www.example.com, into IP addresses that computers can understand. This translation is essential for the functioning of the internet, as it allows users to access websites and services using easy-to-remember domain names instead of complicated IP addresses.
Route 53 is Amazon&amp;rsquo;s reliable and scalable web service for managing DNS.</description></item><item><title>AWS VPC Peering: Connecting and Securing Virtual Private Clouds</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/aws-vpc-peering-beginner-guide/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2024 16:34:44 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://csetutorials.com/aws-vpc-peering-beginner-guide/</guid><description>AWS VPC Peering is a networking feature that allows you to connect two Virtual Private Clouds (VPCs) within the same AWS region or across different regions. It enables you to establish a private and secure connection between VPCs, allowing them to communicate with each other as if they were on the same network.
By leveraging AWS VPC Peering, you can create a virtual network that spans multiple VPCs, enabling seamless communication between resources in different VPCs.</description></item><item><title>AWS Elastic Network Interface (ENI): Exploring the Gateway to Your AWS Infrastructure</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/aws-eni-vpc-beginner-guide-best-practices/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2024 15:17:57 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://csetutorials.com/aws-eni-vpc-beginner-guide-best-practices/</guid><description>Let&amp;rsquo;s dive into the fascinating world of AWS Elastic Network Interface (ENI). If you&amp;rsquo;re new to the cloud computing scene or just curious about this particular AWS service, you&amp;rsquo;ve come to the right place.
What is AWS ENI? AWS ENI, short for Elastic Network Interface, is a virtual network interface that you can attach to an Amazon EC2 instance in your AWS environment. It acts as a gateway between your EC2 instance and the rest of your AWS infrastructure, providing a secure and reliable way for your instances to communicate with each other and the outside world.</description></item><item><title>Understanding AWS Security Group and NACL in AWS</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/aws-security-groups-vs-nacls-control-traffic/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2024 14:47:19 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://csetutorials.com/aws-security-groups-vs-nacls-control-traffic/</guid><description>What is AWS Security Group? AWS Security Group is a fundamental component of Amazon Web Services (AWS) that allows you to control inbound and outbound traffic for your AWS resources. It acts as a virtual firewall for your instances, controlling the traffic that is allowed to reach them.
Each security group contains a set of rules that define the inbound and outbound traffic. These rules are specified by IP protocol, port range, and source or destination IP addresses.</description></item><item><title>NAT Gateways: Securely Connect Private Subnets to the Internet</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/aws-nat-gateway-nat-instance-internet-gateway/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2024 17:20:36 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://csetutorials.com/aws-nat-gateway-nat-instance-internet-gateway/</guid><description>In the dynamic world of cloud networking, AWS NAT Gateways play a vital role in managing network traffic for resources within private subnets. They provide a seamless way to handle Network Address Translation (NAT), enabling secure communication with the internet for your private instances. This article delves into NAT Gateways, their functionalities, how they differ from Internet Gateways, and the factors affecting their pricing, performance, and optimization. We&amp;rsquo;ll also explore the alternative solution of NAT Instances and the trade-offs involved.</description></item><item><title>Understanding AWS Internet Gateway: Benefits, Functionality, and Performance Considerations</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/aws-internet-gateway/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2024 08:01:57 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://csetutorials.com/aws-internet-gateway/</guid><description>The Internet Gateway is a crucial component of AWS networking infrastructure that enables communication between instances in the virtual private cloud (VPC) and the internet. It acts as a bridge, allowing traffic to flow seamlessly between the VPC and the outside world. This means that instances within the VPC can access the internet and be accessed by internet users.
Setting up an Internet Gateway is a straightforward process in AWS. Once created, it can be attached to a VPC, enabling internet connectivity for all instances within that VPC.</description></item><item><title>AWS VPC IP Mastery: Public vs Private vs Elastic IPs</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/aws-vpc-ip-differences-public-private-elastic/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2024 06:59:58 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://csetutorials.com/aws-vpc-ip-differences-public-private-elastic/</guid><description>When it comes to setting up a virtual private cloud (VPC) in Amazon Web Services (AWS), understanding IP addresses is crucial. In this article, we will delve into the different types of IP addresses used in AWS VPC, including private, public, elastic, IPv4, and IPv6 addresses. By the end, you&amp;rsquo;ll have a clear understanding of how these addresses function within the AWS ecosystem.
IP addresses play a vital role in networking, allowing devices to communicate with each other over the internet.</description></item><item><title>Level Up Your VPC: The Power of AWS Route Tables</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/aws-route-tables-for-beginners/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 15:08:10 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://csetutorials.com/aws-route-tables-for-beginners/</guid><description>When it comes to networking in the cloud, AWS offers a powerful service called Route Tables. Route Tables play a crucial role in determining how traffic is routed within your Virtual Private Cloud (VPC) and between your VPC and the outside world. In this article, we will dive deep into AWS Route Tables, exploring their features, configuration options, and providing various examples to help you understand how a sample Route Table would look in each scenario.</description></item><item><title>Conquer VPC Networking: Subnets &amp; CIDR Allocation Mastery</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/vpc-networking-subnet-cidr-beginner-guide/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 11:11:33 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://csetutorials.com/vpc-networking-subnet-cidr-beginner-guide/</guid><description>CIDR Notation and IP Address Allocation CIDR notation is a fundamental concept in networking that allows for efficient allocation of IP addresses. It provides a way to represent IP addresses and their associated subnet masks in a compact and easy-to-understand format. By using CIDR notation, network administrators can allocate IP addresses in a flexible and scalable manner.
In CIDR notation, an IP address is followed by a forward slash (/) and a number, which represents the number of network bits in the address.</description></item><item><title>Unlocking the Power of the AWS Management Console</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/aws-management-console-for-beginners/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 17:37:52 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://csetutorials.com/aws-management-console-for-beginners/</guid><description>When it comes to cloud computing, the AWS Management Console is your gateway to the vast array of services and resources offered by AWS. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re a beginner or an experienced user, understanding how to navigate and utilize the console effectively is crucial for maximizing the benefits of AWS.
The user-friendly interface of the AWS Management Console stands out as one of its primary benefits. With its intuitive design and layout, even those with limited technical knowledge can easily navigate through the console and access the services they need.</description></item><item><title>AWS Networking Foundations: Exploring VPC, TGW, and Private Link</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/aws-vpc-tgw-privatelink-network-connectivity/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 16:41:09 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://csetutorials.com/aws-vpc-tgw-privatelink-network-connectivity/</guid><description>Before we delve into the details of AWS VPC, TGW, and Private Link, let&amp;rsquo;s first understand the importance of networking in the cloud. In traditional on-premises environments, networking was often seen as a complex and time-consuming task. It involved setting up physical hardware, configuring routers, switches, and firewalls, and managing IP address allocations.
However, with the advent of cloud computing, networking has become much more simplified and flexible. AWS, being a leading cloud provider, offers a wide range of networking services that allow users to create and manage virtual networks with ease.</description></item><item><title>Understanding AWS Global Infrastructure: Regions, Availability Zones and Local Zones</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/aws-global-infrastructure-regions-availability-zones/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 14:22:04 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://csetutorials.com/aws-global-infrastructure-regions-availability-zones/</guid><description>When it comes to understanding the AWS global infrastructure, it is essential to grasp the concepts of regions, availability zones, and local zones. These three components work in tandem to ensure that AWS can deliver its services reliably and efficiently to customers all around the world.
Understanding AWS Regions Firstly, let&amp;rsquo;s talk about AWS regions. An AWS region is a geographical area that consists of multiple data centers, also known as Availability Zones (AZs).</description></item><item><title>Public Cloud Demystified: Everything You Need to Know</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/public-cloud-beginner-guide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 17:38:04 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://csetutorials.com/public-cloud-beginner-guide/</guid><description>A public cloud refers to a type of cloud computing service that is available to the general public over the internet. It is owned and operated by a third-party cloud service provider, who is responsible for managing and maintaining the infrastructure and resources.
One of the key characteristics of a public cloud is its multi-tenancy nature. This means that multiple users or organizations can share the same pool of computing resources, such as servers, storage, and networks.</description></item><item><title>Hybrid Cloud: The Best of Both Cloud Worlds</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/hybrid-cloud-beginner-guide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 09:49:37 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://csetutorials.com/hybrid-cloud-beginner-guide/</guid><description>A hybrid cloud is a computing environment that combines the use of both private and public cloud services. It allows organizations to leverage the benefits of both types of clouds, creating a flexible and scalable infrastructure that meets their specific needs.
How Does a Hybrid Cloud Work? In a hybrid cloud environment, organizations typically have a private cloud infrastructure that is located on-premises or in a dedicated data center. This private cloud is connected to one or more public cloud providers through a secure network connection.</description></item><item><title>Private Cloud 101: Your Guide to a Secure &amp; Tailored IT Environment</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/private-cloud-explained-for-beginners/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2024 18:23:42 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://csetutorials.com/private-cloud-explained-for-beginners/</guid><description>In today&amp;rsquo;s digital age, cloud computing has revolutionized the way businesses operate and manage their IT infrastructure. It offers a flexible and scalable solution that allows organizations to access and utilize computing resources over the internet. One of the key variations of cloud computing is the private cloud, which provides a secure and tailored IT environment for businesses.
A private cloud is a cloud setup specifically for one organization&amp;rsquo;s use. Unlike public clouds that are shared by multiple users, a private cloud is designed to meet the specific needs of an individual business.</description></item><item><title>Community Cloud: The Shared Secret to Secure Collaboration</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/community-cloud-computing/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2024 18:14:04 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://csetutorials.com/community-cloud-computing/</guid><description>A community cloud is a type of cloud computing infrastructure that is shared by specific organizations with common interests. It provides a collaborative platform for these organizations to share resources, applications, and data securely. Unlike public clouds that are available to anyone, and private clouds that are dedicated to a single organization, community clouds are designed to meet the unique needs of a specific community.
In a community cloud, multiple organizations with similar requirements come together to pool their resources and create a shared infrastructure.</description></item><item><title>Unlock the Cloud: What is SaaS &amp; Why You Need It</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/software-as-a-service-beginner-guide/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2024 11:43:49 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://csetutorials.com/software-as-a-service-beginner-guide/</guid><description>Imagine a time when using a software program meant physically going to a store, purchasing a box with CDs or DVDs containing the software, and then installing it on your computer. Not too long ago, this was standard practice. Thankfully, today we have a more convenient way to access software: Software as a Service (SaaS). Think of it as software that lives on the internet, accessible from any device with a web browser, just like your favourite social media platform or online bank.</description></item><item><title>Build Like a Pro: Demystifying PaaS for App Development Newbies</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/platform-as-a-service-beginner-guide/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2024 06:17:33 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://csetutorials.com/platform-as-a-service-beginner-guide/</guid><description>Imagine you&amp;rsquo;re building a house. You can approach it in three ways:
Buying the Land and Building Materials (IaaS) : This is like starting from scratch. You&amp;rsquo;d need to buy the land (physical servers), bricks (storage), and lumber (networking) to build your house (application). It gives you the most control, but it&amp;rsquo;s also the most time-consuming and expensive option.
Hiring a Contractor with Prefabricated Walls (PaaS) : This is like using a PaaS platform.</description></item><item><title>Say Goodbye to Hardware Hassle: The Simple Guide to IaaS</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/infrastructure-as-a-service/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 10:22:05 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://csetutorials.com/infrastructure-as-a-service/</guid><description>IaaS, or Infrastructure as a Service, is a transformative concept in cloud computing that offers a way to rent essential IT infrastructure, rather than owning and maintaining it yourself. It&amp;rsquo;s like subscribing to a utility instead of building your own power plant. This shift from physical hardware to virtual resources unlocks a treasure trove of benefits for businesses of all sizes:
Reduced upfront costs: IaaS eliminates the need for hefty upfront investments in physical hardware.</description></item><item><title>Level Up Your Cloud Architecture with AWS Well-Architected Lenses</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/build-flawless-cloud-with-aws-lenses/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2024 17:52:14 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://csetutorials.com/build-flawless-cloud-with-aws-lenses/</guid><description>The AWS Well-Architected Framework provides a foundational set of best practices that act as a roadmap for building secure, efficient, and scalable cloud applications on AWS. These recommended practices are arranged according to six pillars: operational excellence, security, reliability, performance efficiency, cost optimization, and sustainability.
To help you delve deeper into specific aspects of your cloud architecture, AWS offers Well-Architected Lenses. Think of these lenses as specialized filters you can apply to your design.</description></item><item><title>Navigating Cloud Excellence: An In-Depth Look at AWS Well-Architected Framework</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/aws-well-architected-framework-pillars/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2024 16:26:49 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://csetutorials.com/aws-well-architected-framework-pillars/</guid><description>The AWS Well-Architected Framework is basically a checklist for building strong applications on Amazon Web Services (AWS). It&amp;rsquo;s like a recipe that helps you create secure, reliable, efficient, and cost-effective cloud systems. It is built on six pillars that provide a foundation for creating secure, efficient, and reliable cloud applications on Amazon Web Services (AWS). These pillars are:
Operational Excellence focuses on continuously improving processes and procedures to effectively run and monitor systems, delivering business value.</description></item><item><title>Why Businesses Flock to AWS: A Look at Market Share, Influence &amp; Adoption</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/aws-market-share-influence-adoption/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 08:08:53 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://csetutorials.com/aws-market-share-influence-adoption/</guid><description>In recent years, cloud computing has become an indispensable tool for businesses of all sizes. It offers a wide range of advantages over traditional on-premise IT infrastructure, including scalability, agility, cost-efficiency, and improved disaster recovery. By leveraging remote servers and virtualized resources, cloud computing allows businesses to access computing power, storage, databases, and other IT services on-demand, eliminating the need for expensive upfront investments in hardware and software. This flexibility empowers businesses to adapt to changing needs quickly and efficiently, while also enabling them to focus their resources on core competencies rather than IT infrastructure management.</description></item><item><title>On Page SEO while writing a Blog</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/on-page-seo-while-writing-blog/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2023 09:31:08 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://csetutorials.com/on-page-seo-while-writing-blog/</guid><description>Keyword Use in Starting and Ending Para of Content Place your main keyword within the first 100 words. Use in Image Name, Alt Tag and Title Tag Title Of Our Posts Permalink of Posts Keywords in Heading Tags h1, h2… Bold and Italics your keyword and other important Semantics keyword. Use it in Meta Description. Use long tail keywords in place of generic keywords. Instead of keyword, use keyword phrases. Ex:- a single word (i.</description></item><item><title>Scala 3 Basics</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/scala-3-basics/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2022 09:38:50 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://csetutorials.com/scala-3-basics/</guid><description>Scala Basics How to declare a variable Declare a constant variable val x: Int = 42 or
val x = 42 types are optional val cannot be reassigned, val are constant/immutable Semicolon are not necessary Declare a variable var x: Int = 42 or
var x = 42 Expressions &amp;amp; Instructions Changing a variable is called as side effects Instructions are doing something. Expression is something that has a value. Donot write loops in Scala.</description></item><item><title>My All Time Favourite Gnome Extentions</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/gnome-extentions-all-time-favourite/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Aug 2022 07:50:18 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://csetutorials.com/gnome-extentions-all-time-favourite/</guid><description>Dash to Panel This extension moves the dash into the gnome main panel so that the application launchers and system tray are combined into a single panel, similar to Windows. You don&amp;rsquo;t need to install Dash to Dock extention if you install Dash to Panel extention. Refresh Wifi Connections This extension adds a refresh button to the Wi-Fi connection selection dialog to manually request for a network scan.
Window Is Ready - Notification Remover Removes window is ready Notification</description></item><item><title>Distributed Leaderboard System Design</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/distributed-leaderboard-system-design/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 07:21:55 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://csetutorials.com/distributed-leaderboard-system-design/</guid><description>Requirements 100 million requests per second Leaderboard should be updated as soon as possible Components of the system Key-Value database Webservers Load Balancers Cache Service Queues Data Flow Summary The user&amp;rsquo;s request to update score would go to the webservers. The webserver send the request to the queue. From queue, a set of workers fetch the individual request, fetch the user&amp;rsquo;s current score from the key-value db and adding the increment, updating the new score to the db then send the updated score to the batch queue (combining multiple user&amp;rsquo;s scores).</description></item><item><title>Web Crawler Design Techniques</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/web-crawler-design-techniques/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Apr 2021 10:37:44 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://csetutorials.com/web-crawler-design-techniques/</guid><description>A web crawler can be used in various services such as
Search Engines Archive Storage Piracy Detector Web Mining Lets talk about the data flow first. Lets say we have a set of url as a starting point. So first we fetch the content of those urls. After that we parse the content, check if it is duplicate or not. Then we extract urls and after filtering the urls we add those urls to the queue to again crawling.</description></item><item><title>URL Shortener System Design</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/url-shortener-system-design/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Mar 2021 10:36:23 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://csetutorials.com/url-shortener-system-design/</guid><description>Requirements 100 million writes per day ie. 100 million urls would be shortened per day. Only alphanumeric characters are allowed in the shortened URL. The system should be highly available, scalable and fault tolerance. Estimations Write operations : 100 million. It means 100000000/(24 * 3600) = 1158 writes per second. Read operations : Lets say the read operations are 10 times of write operations that is 11580 reads per second. Lets suppose the service would run for 10 years.</description></item><item><title>Unique ID generator in distributed systems</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/unique-id-generator-system-design/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 02:30:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://csetutorials.com/unique-id-generator-system-design/</guid><description>Key Points MySQL auto increment is not sufficient for distributed systems because it is not large enough &amp;amp; would be very challenging generating unique ids across multiple databases with minimal delay;
Our requirement is the ids should be unique, sortable, max 64 bit (8 bytes ie. could fit in long data type in Java).
Three ways using which we can generate UUID UUID is 128 bit. It has very low probability of collusion.</description></item><item><title>How to Design a Key Value Database</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/key-value-storage-design-architecture/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 09:29:42 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://csetutorials.com/key-value-storage-design-architecture/</guid><description>It is a non-relational database. The key must be unique, can be plain text or hashed values. The value can be directly fetched through the key.
Requirements The size of a key value pair is small ie. less than 10 KB. Big Data : It should be able to store very large amount of data. High Availability : The system should repond to queries even in case of failures. High Scalability : The system should be able to scale according to the data and the traffic.</description></item><item><title>Consistent Hashing Design and Techniques</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/consistent-hashing-design-techniques/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 07:09:36 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://csetutorials.com/consistent-hashing-design-techniques/</guid><description>Consistent Hashing is one of the very important concept in the field of system designing. Consistent hashing is used mainly in load balancers, key-value store etc.
Lets suppose You have to create a Load Balancer for your WebApp. I presume you know what is a load balancer.
One way is to distribute the load one by one on each server as the request comes. The problem in this approach is that if the server was storing some information in its cache or session then the cache or the session would become irrelevant if the same reqeust for that client goes to another server.</description></item><item><title>Rate Limiter Design Techniques with Scenarios and Solutions</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/rate-limiter-design-techniques/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2021 09:35:32 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://csetutorials.com/rate-limiter-design-techniques/</guid><description>Rate Limiting is a very vast topic. It depends on what type of rate limiter you want, what are your requirements. First lets assume there is a lot of traffic coming every second or minute. So we will do all the calculations according to the rate limiter.
NOTE : There should be minimal impact of rate limiter on apis latency.
How to limit the traffic? To put a control on traffic or a user who is sending a lot of requests, we have to put a middleware (rate limiter) between the internet traffic (ie.</description></item><item><title>SSTable Architecture Summary</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/sstable-architecture/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 10:38:50 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://csetutorials.com/sstable-architecture/</guid><description>Key Points SSTable or Sorted String Table is used to store key values. In SSTables, key-value pairs are written in sorted order in disk. For faster access to value of a key, indexes are maintained for SSTable. Lets call it SSIndex. We keep copy of SSIndex in RAM for faster access. There is a special property of SSTable that is they are immutable. It means we cannot append or delete data to SSTable so as to maintain sorting order and read speed.</description></item><item><title>Passwordless SSH on Ubuntu Linux</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/passwordless-ssh-ubuntu-linux/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2020 09:34:10 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://csetutorials.com/passwordless-ssh-ubuntu-linux/</guid><description>These steps are verified and tested several times and works flawlessly.
Install openssh server
sudo apt-get install openssh-server Remove previous .ssh directory (from home directory)
rm -r ~/.ssh/ Now Execute the below command. Leave all the field empty when asked.
ssh-keygen -t rsa Execute the following commands after that
cat ~/.ssh/id_rsa.pub &amp;gt;&amp;gt; ~/.ssh/authorized_keys sudo chmod go-w ~/ chmod 700 ~/.ssh chmod 600 ~/.ssh/authorized_keys exec ssh-agent bash ssh-add That&amp;rsquo;s it.
You can test on your machine.</description></item><item><title>Top Chrome Extensions for Advanced users and Developers</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/top-chrome-extensions-for-advanced-users-and-developers/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2020 09:10:36 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://csetutorials.com/top-chrome-extensions-for-advanced-users-and-developers/</guid><description>Below is the list of extensions that every developer should install in their Chrome browser. These plugins make the life of developers easy.
Below is the list of extensions that every developer should install in their Chrome browser. These plugins make the life of developers easy.
Adblock Plus : Improves readability of site by blocking all ADDS
Ghostery : Improves browsing experience and speed by blocking all trackers like Analytics, Advertising, Beacons, Privacy and Widgets.</description></item><item><title>How to setup Single Node Hive on Tez Hadoop Cluster</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/setup-hadoop-2-hive-mysql-tez/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2020 08:11:36 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://csetutorials.com/setup-hadoop-2-hive-mysql-tez/</guid><description>In this tutorial I&amp;rsquo;m going to show you how setup single node Hadoop cluster with hive and tez. We are going to use the following versions -
Hadoop - 2.7.2
Hive - 2.1.1
Tez - 0.9.2
Preriquisites : Java 8 must be installed and set JAVA_HOME path. If you are using ubuntu then you can install java by using the below command
sudo apt install openjdk-8-jdk After that you can set JAVA_HOME path by adding the below line in .</description></item><item><title>How to create a seedbox using AWS</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/create-seedbox-aws/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Mar 2020 07:14:31 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://csetutorials.com/create-seedbox-aws/</guid><description>In this article I&amp;rsquo;m going to tell you how to create a seedbox using AWS (Amazon Web Service). Using seedbox we can download torrent files like Ubuntu disk image etc.
To create a seedbox first I will create a aws lambda instance (virtual machine) and then activate seedbox using cloud-torrent. So here are the steps.
1. Login to you aws account. If you don&amp;rsquo;t have an aws account then create it and then login.</description></item><item><title>How to load Vue Components directly to html js</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/load-vue-files-directly-html-js/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Mar 2020 08:37:40 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://csetutorials.com/load-vue-files-directly-html-js/</guid><description>In this tutorial I am going to show you how you could load .vue files or components directly to html/js unlike full fledged vuejs project in which you have to compile project every time.
If some of you know Angular 1.x versions, then you know that how it was easy to add the modules, in which you have to add js files to index.html and after hitting F5 you could see changes.</description></item><item><title>Jersey Server Side Events Tutorial</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/jersey-sse-tutorial/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2019 08:43:01 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://csetutorials.com/jersey-sse-tutorial/</guid><description>In this article I&amp;rsquo;m going to explain what is SSE (Server Side Events) and after that will show you an example.
What is SSE? In general scenario when we want to send something to the client, then client creates a requests to the server. After that the server fetches necessary information / data and sends to the client and then connection is closed. Suppose what if the time to fetch the data is very long.</description></item><item><title>How to run threadsafe code in PHP</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/threadsafe-code-in-php/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2019 09:09:18 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://csetutorials.com/threadsafe-code-in-php/</guid><description>Suppose you have a php file in which there is a code block which you want thread safe. It means, if that php file is being called from many places simultaneously and you want the code block to be executed one by one irrespective of being called at the same time by different places. So here is the theory :
Create a temporary directory if not exits. Check whether temporary directory is empty or not.</description></item><item><title>What is Amazon Web Services</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/what-is-amazon-web-services/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2018 10:39:52 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://csetutorials.com/what-is-amazon-web-services/</guid><description>Let&amp;rsquo;s imagine how life would have been without Spotify. For those who are hearing about Spotify for the first time, Spotify is an online music service offering and it offers instant access to over 16 million licence to songs. Spotify now uses AWS cloud to store the data and share it with their customers.
Prior to AWS they had some issues. Back then users were often getting errors because Spotify could not keep up with the increased demand for storage every new day and that led to users getting upset and users canceling the subscription.</description></item><item><title>How to resize images on Ubuntu Linux</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/how-to-resize-images-on-ubuntu-linux/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2018 09:23:01 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://csetutorials.com/how-to-resize-images-on-ubuntu-linux/</guid><description>Most of the times resizing images on Ubuntu is very difficult. I think some users use Gimp which is a very famous image editor on linux and its like photoshop of Ubuntu. But most of the times I found Gimp very hard to learn. Some people who don&amp;rsquo;t know Gimp like me use online image editors to resize their photos. So here I am going to tell you the alternative of Gimp app to resize your apps.</description></item><item><title>How to install influxdb without root access on Linux</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/install-influxdb-without-root-access-linux/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2018 09:28:01 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://csetutorials.com/install-influxdb-without-root-access-linux/</guid><description>Influxdb time series database is one of the fastest timeseries database. It is current the best aws time series database. Its purely written in go language. It is opensource and is used for recording metrics, events and performing analytics. The steps to install influxdb on various linux distributions (aws influxdb or azure) are available on its download page. But there is one problem in install instructions and that is all requires root access.</description></item><item><title>How to write C or C++ programs on Ubuntu Linux</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/compile-c-programs-on-ubuntu-linux/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 07:05:41 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://csetutorials.com/compile-c-programs-on-ubuntu-linux/</guid><description>If you are a newbie in the linux world you are the facing the question - how to compile c program in linux or how to compile c++ program in linux. So in this post I&amp;rsquo;m going to explain the steps using which you can run your c c++ programs on linux.
There are two ways to write and run C and C++ programs on Ubuntu.
Using command line Using IDE (app) Using command line To run a C or C++ program on linux, there are three phases write code, compile code and run it.</description></item><item><title>How to convert videos in Ubuntu using Vlc</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/convert-videos-ubuntu-using-vlc/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Mar 2018 07:11:21 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://csetutorials.com/convert-videos-ubuntu-using-vlc/</guid><description>In this post I&amp;rsquo;m going to tell you how to convert videos in Ubuntu using vlc. In my opinion vlc is the best free video converter software. So here are the steps.
Install vlc
sudo apt-get install vlc Install other required packages
sudo apt-get install ffmpeg libav-tools gstreamer1.0-libav gstreamer1.0-plugins-bad ubuntu-restricted-extras libde265-dev Open Vlc
Open Menu bar &amp;gt; Media &amp;gt; Convert/Save Now in File tab add the file and click on convert/save.</description></item><item><title>The Finest Android Apps</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/android-apps/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2017 06:26:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://csetutorials.com/android-apps/</guid><description>Busybox (Root Required) : This application is an BusyBox installer for Android.
Flud : Flud is a simple and beautiful BitTorrent client. It is better that utorrent and any other torrent clients available on play store.
Gallery Doctor : It identifies similar, duplicate and bad quality photos and gives you an option to remove them. It is very helpful to remove unwanted whatsapp photos.
Greenify : It forcefully kills apps like facebook and whatsapp that runs in the background, consuming battery and internet bandwidth, push annoying notification.</description></item><item><title>How to setup Kerberos on Ubuntu</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/setup-kerberos-ubuntu/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2017 08:40:58 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://csetutorials.com/setup-kerberos-ubuntu/</guid><description>In a network, there is one machine which acts as a server for Kerberos authentication and rest of the machines act as clients. On the server machine, we will install Kerberos administrative server and database for Kerberos. On client machines, we will install Kerberos client. So first we will setup Kerberos server.
Setting Kerberos Server Execute the below command to install Kerberos admin server and KDE (key distribution center).
sudo apt install krb5-kdc krb5-admin-server It will ask you the following three things one by one</description></item><item><title>Ubuntu Apps</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/ubuntu-apps/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2017 09:39:46 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://csetutorials.com/ubuntu-apps/</guid><description>Chromium One of the best open source web browser in the world.
sudo apt-get install chromium-browser Unity Tweak Tool Unity Tweak Tool is a settings manager for the Unity desktop. It provides users with a fast, simple and easy-to-use interface with which to access many useful and little known features and settings of the desktop environment that one may want to configure.
sudo apt-get install unity-tweak-tool GDebi Gdebi is a simple tool to install deb files, simple and much faster than ubuntu software center.</description></item><item><title>Things to do with Firefox after installation</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/things-to-do-firefox/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 May 2017 09:16:43 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://csetutorials.com/things-to-do-firefox/</guid><description>NOTE : This post is not applicable for Firefox Quantum
We know that Firefox is one of the most popular browsers in the world. But to make the most out of it, we have to configure it. So I have noted down some important tasks. Here is the TODO list :
Delete blotted bookmarks Set default folder for saving bookmarks Disable firefox health report Disable auto update search engines Enable search suggestions Install Fast Dial addon Install Ghostry addon Install DownThemAll addon Install FlashGot addon Install Menu Wizard addon Delete blotted bookmarks Open Menu Bookmarks &amp;gt; Show All Bookmarks</description></item><item><title>My Ubuntu Notes</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/my-ubuntu-notes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 May 2017 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://csetutorials.com/my-ubuntu-notes/</guid><description>During Installation, always create swap space and a separate partition for the Home directory. Always select that partition for other Linux distributions also but do not format it. And create separate users for different-different distributions like /home/ubuntu for Ubuntu, /home/arch for arch Linux and so on.
If your system has SSD then donot create swap space from SSD.
Use Ubuntu Source List generator.
Run sudo command without password
If you don&amp;rsquo;t want to type sudo password again and again then run command sudo visudo and append the below line at the end.</description></item><item><title>Redirect Non www to www using UrlRewriteFilter in Web Servers</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/redirect-non-www-using-urlrewritefilter-web-servers/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2016 09:37:22 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://csetutorials.com/redirect-non-www-using-urlrewritefilter-web-servers/</guid><description>On apache servers usually we redirect by modifying .htaccess file. But it doesn&amp;rsquo;t work on web apps that are hosted on servers like tomcat, jboss etc. So in this case we&amp;rsquo;ll use a Java Web Filter called UrlRewriteFilter. It allows us to change url before they hit the apis. It is compatible with all web servers (Apache Tomcat, JBoss, Jetty etc.). Its licence is BSD-3-Clause
If you want the latest jar then you can take the latest pull from its github repository and compile it using command mvn clean install.</description></item><item><title>What is the difference between public, private, protected and default?</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/difference-public-private-protected-default/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2016 07:19:38 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://csetutorials.com/difference-public-private-protected-default/</guid><description>Public, Private and Protected are known as Access Modifiers. In most programming languages there is another access modifier and that is known as &amp;lsquo;default&amp;rsquo;. In C++ there are 3 access modifies public, private and protected. In Java there are four access modifier public, private, protected and default.
In java if we don&amp;rsquo;t specify any access modifier in methods or fields, it assumes as &amp;lsquo;default&amp;rsquo; but in C++ it assumes as &amp;lsquo;private&amp;rsquo;.</description></item><item><title>How to obfuscate jar or war file using yguard</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/obfuscate-jar-or-war-file-using-yguard/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2016 08:15:24 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://csetutorials.com/obfuscate-jar-or-war-file-using-yguard/</guid><description>YGuard is a free Java bytecode obfuscator and shrinker. It is one of the best code obfuscation tools. It improves your software deployment by prohibiting undesirable access to your source code. It is free and protect code from reverse engineering. It can obfuscate Names and shrinks Code.
YGuard is an Ant Task. It means it can be run through ant. If you are using maven then you would need a plugin called maven-antrun-plugin.</description></item><item><title>Deploy Angular Maven WebApp on Tomcat</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/deploy-angular-2-maven-webapp-on-tomcat/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2016 07:16:16 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://csetutorials.com/deploy-angular-2-maven-webapp-on-tomcat/</guid><description>In this post I&amp;rsquo;m going to show you how you could integrate Angular with Maven automatically. I request you to read this article carefully and not for just copy paste because it would be very helpful for you in various ways like debugging, tweaking or modifying steps etc.
First of all here is the summary of the steps for integration Setup nodejs and npm Run command npm install in angular directory to install dependencies and compile typescript files.</description></item><item><title>Influxdb Tutorial</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/influxdb-tutorial/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2016 07:55:18 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://csetutorials.com/influxdb-tutorial/</guid><description>Influxdata is a platform for storing, collecting, visualizing and managing time-series data. Currently Influxdb is the most famous time series database. This article is for version 1.x only.
The following topics that I am going to cover in this article.
Influxdb Installation Databases Inserting Data Querying Data Tags in influxdb Group by time Query Deleting measurement or data from measurement Retention Policies In influxdb the combination of timestamp and tags is composite keys.</description></item></channel></rss>