<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Java on Cse Tutorials</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/topics/java/</link><description>Recent content in Java on Cse Tutorials</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2016 15:39:36 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://csetutorials.com/topics/java/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>What is the difference between public, private, protected and default?</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/difference-public-private-protected-default.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2016 07:19:38 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://csetutorials.com/difference-public-private-protected-default.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Public, Private and Protected are known as Access Modifiers. In most programming languages there is another access modifier and that is known as &amp;lsquo;default&amp;rsquo;. In C++ there are 3 access modifies public, private and protected. In Java there are four access modifier public, private, protected and default.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In java if we don&amp;rsquo;t specify any access modifier in methods or fields, it assumes as &amp;lsquo;default&amp;rsquo; but in C++ it assumes as &amp;lsquo;private&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How to obfuscate jar or war file using yguard</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/obfuscate-jar-or-war-file-using-yguard.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2016 08:15:24 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://csetutorials.com/obfuscate-jar-or-war-file-using-yguard.html</guid><description>&lt;p>YGuard is a free Java bytecode obfuscator and shrinker. It is one of the best code obfuscation tools. It improves your software deployment by prohibiting undesirable access to your source code. It is free and protect code from reverse engineering. It can obfuscate Names and shrinks Code.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>YGuard is an Ant Task. It means it can be run through ant. If you are using maven then you would need a plugin called &lt;code>maven-antrun-plugin&lt;/code>. You can call ant script from pom.xml using this plugin. Here the code for calling ant script using maven.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>