<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Big Data on Cse Tutorials</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/topics/big-data/</link><description>Recent content in Big Data on Cse Tutorials</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 06:40:58 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://csetutorials.com/topics/big-data/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Understanding NiFi and Airflow in Simple Terms: How They Help with Data Engineering and Data Flow</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/nifi-vs-airflow-real-time-vs-batch/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 06:40:58 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://csetutorials.com/nifi-vs-airflow-real-time-vs-batch/</guid><description>In the world of data, things can get pretty complex. Companies have tons of data flowing in from different sources—like websites, sensors, apps, or databases—and they need ways to handle and process all of this information. Two tools that help manage this data are Apache NiFi and Apache Airflow. They do different jobs, but both are very important when it comes to making sure data is handled properly. Let’s break it down in simple terms.</description></item><item><title>Scala 3 Basics</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/scala-3-basics/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2022 09:38:50 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://csetutorials.com/scala-3-basics/</guid><description>Scala Basics How to declare a variable Declare a constant variable val x: Int = 42 or
val x = 42 types are optional val cannot be reassigned, val are constant/immutable Semicolon are not necessary Declare a variable var x: Int = 42 or
var x = 42 Expressions &amp;amp; Instructions Changing a variable is called as side effects Instructions are doing something. Expression is something that has a value. Donot write loops in Scala.</description></item><item><title>How to setup Single Node Hive on Tez Hadoop Cluster</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/setup-hadoop-2-hive-mysql-tez/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2020 08:11:36 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://csetutorials.com/setup-hadoop-2-hive-mysql-tez/</guid><description>In this tutorial I&amp;rsquo;m going to show you how setup single node Hadoop cluster with hive and tez. We are going to use the following versions -
Hadoop - 2.7.2
Hive - 2.1.1
Tez - 0.9.2
Preriquisites : Java 8 must be installed and set JAVA_HOME path. If you are using ubuntu then you can install java by using the below command
sudo apt install openjdk-8-jdk After that you can set JAVA_HOME path by adding the below line in .</description></item></channel></rss>