<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Web Development on Cse Tutorials</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/topics/web-development/</link><description>Recent content in Web Development on Cse Tutorials</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 15:38:21 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://csetutorials.com/topics/web-development/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Understanding Multithreading and Asyncio in Python: A Deep Dive into I/O-bound Task Management</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/multithreading-vs-asyncio-python-io-bound-tasks/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 15:38:21 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://csetutorials.com/multithreading-vs-asyncio-python-io-bound-tasks/</guid><description>When building applications in Python, particularly those that handle numerous I/O-bound tasks (e.g., file reading/writing, network requests), choosing the right concurrency model—multithreading or asyncio—is crucial for performance. Both approaches aim to optimize how tasks are executed concurrently, but they differ in how they handle context switching, resource management, and complexity. In this article, we’ll explore the nuances, concerns, and trade-offs of multithreading and asyncio in Python, especially when dealing with I/O-bound tasks.</description></item><item><title>On Page SEO while writing a Blog</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/on-page-seo-while-writing-blog/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2023 09:31:08 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://csetutorials.com/on-page-seo-while-writing-blog/</guid><description>Keyword Use in Starting and Ending Para of Content Place your main keyword within the first 100 words. Use in Image Name, Alt Tag and Title Tag Title Of Our Posts Permalink of Posts Keywords in Heading Tags h1, h2… Bold and Italics your keyword and other important Semantics keyword. Use it in Meta Description. Use long tail keywords in place of generic keywords. Instead of keyword, use keyword phrases. Ex:- a single word (i.</description></item><item><title>How to load Vue Components directly to html js</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/load-vue-files-directly-html-js/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Mar 2020 08:37:40 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://csetutorials.com/load-vue-files-directly-html-js/</guid><description>In this tutorial I am going to show you how you could load .vue files or components directly to html/js unlike full fledged vuejs project in which you have to compile project every time.
If some of you know Angular 1.x versions, then you know that how it was easy to add the modules, in which you have to add js files to index.html and after hitting F5 you could see changes.</description></item><item><title>Jersey Server Side Events Tutorial</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/jersey-sse-tutorial/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2019 08:43:01 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://csetutorials.com/jersey-sse-tutorial/</guid><description>In this article I&amp;rsquo;m going to explain what is SSE (Server Side Events) and after that will show you an example.
What is SSE? In general scenario when we want to send something to the client, then client creates a requests to the server. After that the server fetches necessary information / data and sends to the client and then connection is closed. Suppose what if the time to fetch the data is very long.</description></item><item><title>How to run threadsafe code in PHP</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/threadsafe-code-in-php/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2019 09:09:18 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://csetutorials.com/threadsafe-code-in-php/</guid><description>Suppose you have a php file in which there is a code block which you want thread safe. It means, if that php file is being called from many places simultaneously and you want the code block to be executed one by one irrespective of being called at the same time by different places. So here is the theory :
Create a temporary directory if not exits. Check whether temporary directory is empty or not.</description></item><item><title>Redirect Non www to www using UrlRewriteFilter in Web Servers</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/redirect-non-www-using-urlrewritefilter-web-servers/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2016 09:37:22 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://csetutorials.com/redirect-non-www-using-urlrewritefilter-web-servers/</guid><description>On apache servers usually we redirect by modifying .htaccess file. But it doesn&amp;rsquo;t work on web apps that are hosted on servers like tomcat, jboss etc. So in this case we&amp;rsquo;ll use a Java Web Filter called UrlRewriteFilter. It allows us to change url before they hit the apis. It is compatible with all web servers (Apache Tomcat, JBoss, Jetty etc.). Its licence is BSD-3-Clause
If you want the latest jar then you can take the latest pull from its github repository and compile it using command mvn clean install.</description></item><item><title>How to obfuscate jar or war file using yguard</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/obfuscate-jar-or-war-file-using-yguard/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2016 08:15:24 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://csetutorials.com/obfuscate-jar-or-war-file-using-yguard/</guid><description>YGuard is a free Java bytecode obfuscator and shrinker. It is one of the best code obfuscation tools. It improves your software deployment by prohibiting undesirable access to your source code. It is free and protect code from reverse engineering. It can obfuscate Names and shrinks Code.
YGuard is an Ant Task. It means it can be run through ant. If you are using maven then you would need a plugin called maven-antrun-plugin.</description></item><item><title>Deploy Angular Maven WebApp on Tomcat</title><link>https://csetutorials.com/deploy-angular-2-maven-webapp-on-tomcat/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2016 07:16:16 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://csetutorials.com/deploy-angular-2-maven-webapp-on-tomcat/</guid><description>In this post I&amp;rsquo;m going to show you how you could integrate Angular with Maven automatically. I request you to read this article carefully and not for just copy paste because it would be very helpful for you in various ways like debugging, tweaking or modifying steps etc.
First of all here is the summary of the steps for integration Setup nodejs and npm Run command npm install in angular directory to install dependencies and compile typescript files.</description></item></channel></rss>